Summary.

DevOps Engineer with 10+ years of experience - from managing VMs on bare-metal to leading teams managing PolyCloud Operations; I have expertise in Container orchestration, Cloud, CI-CD and Infrastructure-as-Code workflows. I believe in everything-as-code and would love to embrace the emerging technologies.

Work Experience

Retraced GmbH Germany

DEVOPS ENGINEER

May. 2023 -

- Lead DevOps team own all Cloud Operations, CI/CD, Infrastructure-As-Code workflows and all things automation
- Desinged and built Self Service developers can spin up a microservice with a single-click under 10 minutes from what used to take more than 3 hours.
- Led and executed the project to make organization ISO27001 compliant for 2 consecutive years from drafting organizational structures to enforcing Controls
- Single Click Disaster Recovery spins up the frontend on Cloudflare, Kubernetes Cluster and Database.
- Optimized datadog usage and brough down costs by 30percent
- · Owned all things security managing the penetration testing and mitigaing all vulnerabilities and Continuously enhancing security.

Inforcduced Kong API Gateway to easily connect all API microservices and simplify endpoint management.

Hyderabad, India

LEAD DEVOPS ENGINEER Nov.2020 - April 2023

- Lead the project in transforming into Microservices on Openshift leveraging helm charts and Argo CD.
- As a Lead, offering guidance to the DevOps engineers working on various projects on the best practices and right tools for specific use-case scenarios.
- Managed multiple Cloud operations from automating building CIS compliant images for a banking client to Terraforming entire stack on AWS and Azure.
- Designed scalable CI/CD pipelines and configuration management frameworks for microservices on Kubernetes with Azure DevOps and GitHub

Axelerant Hyderabad, India

SITE RELIABILITY ENGINEER

December.2019 - October 2020

- Designed and built repeatable multi-cloud Infrastructure as code templates with templates to provision resources to create highly available Kubernetes Cluster.
- · Led the project to migrate a monolith on-premise application to microservics on Cloud from Dockerizing to helmizing the entire project.
- · Created Branch based deployments leveraging Kuberentes namespaces and Environments on GitLabCI

Skills

DevOps | AWS | Cloudflare | Kubernetes | Azure | Linux | Terraform | GitHub Actions | SQL | nodejs | Python | Ansible |

Education

Andhra University

B.Sc in Computer Science

Visakhapatnam, India

Jun. 2003 - Apr. 2006